Heather Van Tassel

Data Scientist

Skilled data scientist with 3 years of industry experience. Passionate about creating reproducible statistical analyses and data visualizations that tell stories that shift human perception and actions in the field of personalized medicine and wellness.

Work History

2022-03-

2022-00-	Data Sciennisi
2022-02 -	Visier, Vancouver, BC
2023-02	Software algorithm development and research with millions of HR employee records. Created 10 new benchmarks and Insights Report on applicant rates across industries.
2020-08 -	Data Scientist
2022-02	Viewpoint AI, Vancouver, BC

Machine learning, statistical algorithms and data visualization development in gaile software team for a collaborative decision making software startup.

2020-03 -**Data Scientist** 2020-06

Imbellus, Vancouver, BC

Data Scientist

• Statistical analysis of test-taker performance across forms for psychometric models in R. Code reviews of python scoring pipeline in agile scrum team.

2019-09 -**Data Scientist** 2020-02

Floka, Women's Wellness platform. Vancouver, BC

- Created clustering algorithms, correlations and regressions to provide internal reports for improved understanding of user's health behaviours using data from 200 different wellness apps.
- Built and maintained cloud infrastructure for deploying machine learning models and improved personalized wellness recommendation system model.

2019-04 -Data Scientist - Capstone project 2019-06

E-comm 911, Vancouver, BC

 Improve data management strategy by creating a reproducible data integration pipeline from 4 departments for: 1) attrition analysis using survival analysis and regression models for analyzing factors affecting employee retention and 2) short-term absence classification model to predict whether employees will be absent.

Contact

Address

Vancouver, BC, V5V 1B1

Phone

778-751-7346

E-mail

heathervt12@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in /heather-van-tassel/

https://heathervant.github.io/

Skills



Pandas

NumPy

Time series analysis

Regression modeling

Natural Language **Processing**

• Present results to key stakeholders and collaborate with multiple departments to guide staffing model.

2017-01 -2017-08

Research Project Manager

BC Children's Hospital, Vancouver, BC

- Executed research plan for assessing the opinion of 100 pediatric biobank stakeholders.
- Performed qualitative and quantitative analysis.
- Processed patient blood, tissue, and urine samples for different studies, data entry, large database inventory management, clinical consenting with children, families, and women for multiple studies.

Education

2020-11

AWS Academy Cloud Architecting Course. COMP 3215 - BC Institute of Technology, online.

2018-08 -2019-06

Master's of Science: Data Science

University of British Columbia - Vancouver Course Projects available on https://aithub.com/heathervant:

- Collaborative R shiny app for visualizing qualitative and quantitative <u>survey response data</u>.
- Collaborative software package in <u>R</u> and <u>Python</u> for dataframe cleaning.
- Reproducible 2-way ANOVA <u>analysis pipeline</u> of viral DNA using Docker and Make files.

2012-08 -2018-05

Bachelor of Science: Integrated Science, Biochemistry and Neuroscience

University of British Columbia - Vancouver, BC Coursework included: Physiology and Cellular Neurobiology, Psychopharmacology, and Membrane Biochemistry

2014-09 -2015-06

Exchange Student: Physiology and Neuroscience

University of California San Diego

Achievements

- 2018 + 2019 Hackseq participant. UBC. Teracyc <u>viral voyager</u> shiny app, and antimicrobial resistance clinical <u>analysis pipeline</u>
- April 2019. Women in Data Science UBC conference at UBC Ambassador and host.
- 2012-2014. Varsity Athlete, University of British Columbia Track and Cross-country runner

Publications

Zaidi FN, Cicchini V, Kaufman D, Ko E, Ko A, Van Tassel H, Whitehead MC. Innervation of Taste Buds Revealed with Brainbow Labeling in Mouse. *Journal of Anatomy*. Dec. 2016

Shih J, Kong C, Dittrick M, Van Tassel H, Tarling T, Vercauteren S. Biobank awareness changes opinions of adolescents and parents on participation and practices. Journal of Pediatrics. Under review. March. 2020 Forecastina

Keras

••••

Data Visualization



Written and Verbal communication

••••

AWS cloud services

••••

HTML

SQI



Volunteer Experience:

- Presentation on post-concussion brain health for UBC's mental health network, and started my own brain health coaching business.
- Speaker at The Climate Action Young Leaders Summit 2020

Travel Experience:

- Lived in BC, Canada.
 Italy, California,
 Washington. US +
 Canadian citizen
- Visited: Costa Rica,
 Belgium, France, UK,
 Wales, Greece, Israel,
 Hungary, Austria,
 Brazil, Peru.